Hello world. We're in Fukushima and
currently my little drone is getting
swept away by the wind. I'm [music]
desperately trying to fly back to Kina
Castle. We're here as part of a two-day
trip sponsored by the Prefecture of
Fukushima. We're going to visit
limestone caves, a couple castles, the
elite school for children of samurai,
>> take a small [music] cat train to an old
post station town, and eat some good
food. Speaking of which, the first thing
we did after we safely got the drone
back was to fuel up at a local ramen
shop
with Shiraawa ramen. The soup is a clear
light soy sauce-based broth made from
chicken and pork bones. Handmade curly
noodles are a signature feature
originally crafted using soba noodle
techniques. Common toppings are green
onions, chashu, which is pork, [music]
menma, which are bamboo shoots, naruto
fishcake, and spinach. This restaurant
also had the option of adding wanttons,
which I did.
foreign.
[laughter]
[snorts]
Let's
go.
>> [music]
>> I'm glad I ordered the
>> wanton.
>> Up in the sky over here, this is where
we almost lost our drone. The wind was
so strong it just pushed the drone way
over there and I didn't realize we were
in cinema mode. So, it just kept on
flying that way, but we got it back
luckily.
[music]
>> So, they used to have the gate over
here, but that must have got burned down
a long time ago. And so, now this is the
rendering of what it'll look like when
they're done.
It'll be nice though. It'll be cool.
>> It'll look like this, right?
>> 1868 in the Binian War, right around the
major restoration.
That's when the castle was basically
burned down. Tofu.
The walls you're looking at now were
reconstructed after the To<unk>hoku
earthquake in 2011.
You can see the surviving wall behind.
The region was in the middle of Coyo,
the changing of the leaves.
These, by the way, are shachihoko,
mythical creatures with the head of a
tiger or dragon, the body of a carp, and
their tails pointing towards the
heavens. They are said to have the
capability of summoning water, which
makes sense as wooden castles almost
always end up getting burnt down.
>> This is one of 100 beautiful castles in
Japan.
>> Beautiful fingernails, too.
Mol machicolations.
>> The machicians were used to drop stones
and pour hot water on invaders. Ouch.
[music]
>> Yeah.
>> Very steep.
>> I mean, for a place that was designed
for killing invaders and whatnot, I kind
of found it cute. The handcarved [music]
wood added a lot of charm. And these
secret holes, perfect for ambushing
enemies.
I guess if you're my mother, you would
be climbing up [music] here. I don't
think my mom would like these ropes.
Mom, reply in the comments. Would you
like climbing up here or not? Oh, this
look. It's like a tree fort in here.
Ski. Ski. Ski.
Sunday night.
>> Tofu miru. Oh, this is rock chocolates.
>> This a recommended. You got to buy it
then. Oh, you can get the ramen in here.
>> We need a sword, too. You like the
sword, Ako?
>> You want a sword?
>> Sword? Yeah.
It's a kasa.
>> You got to go in the light. It's very
thick, right?
Okay.
Does taste like tofu.
H.
>> Let's see.
>> What do you think? Your first try of
tofu milk,
>> right?
>> It really tastes like raw tofu.
>> Nama. Nama tofu.
>> I want to see it.
>> [music]
>> What are we going to get?
Isn't that cute?
>> Mountain grape.
>> Let's eat that, too. Yeah, let's do
adventure.
You can't drink in here today.
>> You're strong, Ako. You're fine.
>> We're going into the cave.
[laughter]
You said it was 15°.
It's 9.9.
>> Luckily, I brought my jacket.
>> Your head. You got to watch your head,
right? This kind of feels like Star
Wars.
>> Star Wars.
>> Whoa.
>> I'm going to hit [music] myself
sometime.
This is cool.
Oh, it's moss.
We're going on the adventure course now.
This water dripping down. Oh, it's
beautiful. Ethel.
>> Beautiful.
>> It's a cool cave.
Echo. Echo. Echo. Echo.
Luckily, I'm not tall.
You did it. Congratulations.
You
>> got to go under.
>> What is this? Got to walk.
>> [music]
>> Watch your feet. Watch your hands. Watch
your head.
This one too.
This almost seems fake. [music]
[laughter]
>> Oh my goodness.
I don't think she's going to forgive me
for this.
>> She's down the hole.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. This is warmer over
here. Okay, I think it's almost done.
The adventure course. Let's look at
this.
The green cave. It's not really green.
It's just the light shining on it.
Oo,
the exploration course exit.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Good job.
Good job.
>> You got your money.
[singing]
Oh, this is cool. This is cool.
[music]
>> In case you need Wi-Fi while you're
exploring the caves,
>> Wi-Fi,
it's going to fall on you. Those spikes.
That's scary though.
Overload.
Too much cave.
Too much cave. [music]
Oh, this is Christmas tree. We wish you
a merry Christmas. We wish you a merry
Christmas. We wish you a merry Christmas
and a happy new year. So quiet in here
and there's no one here.
No one at all. Are these wine bottles?
>> Wine or
wine.
This is Ako's kind of cave.
>> I don't know. But it's good at 15° C.
Apparently, the wine likes this
temperature.
>> Yeah. This is how you do it. Look at the
beautiful view.
This tastes like ice cream I had when I
was a kid.
>> That's a nice view.
Look at this big place [music] I'm in.
Look at all the bed I got.
[laughter]
Don't worry, she got a nice room as
well.
All right, so where are we starting?
Like a little bit a little bit, right?
Hi.
[music]
>> I think I got two. This is
two people's
Yeah, we should have got the hot stuff
last.
>> And some meat
and healthy stuff.
Even before breakfast, Ako was hard at
work capturing the beautiful scenery
just outside the window.
And even though we arrived before the
breakfast buffet was to begin being
served, there was already a lineup. I
guess we should have came after 8.
[music] This morning, Ako went for
typical Japanese breakfast fair.
I on the other hand chose something a
bit more western.
[music]
>> One more time. One more.
>> One more time.
>> And with breakfast in our bellies, we
set forth to make our pilgrimage to the
former post town of Ochiuku.
But before we arrived at the station, we
needed to capture some of the stunning
scenery of the Ura Bandai area. With the
clouds rolling across the mountains and
lakes, the sun shone through like a
little slice of heaven across the
landscape.
Sadly, I didn't get to get a closer look
at Mount Bandai, which in 1888 was the
cause of one of the worst volcanic
eruptions in modern Japanese history.
For those of you that enjoy the rumbling
rhythmic sounds of locomotives, you're
in luck. I'm going no BGM for the ride.
Right now, we're going to get on the cat
train and we'll see if there are
actually cats as station attendants
there.
It's a cat train. It's a little cute
cats.
Sakura, station master cat, we're going
to come see you, Sakura.
5 seconds
left.
Take 18 moment.
Yeah.
I should mention we received special
permission to film and photograph
Sakura. We're told she gets nervous in
front of cameras, so there's usually no
photography allowed. But if you want her
image, there's no lack of merch to
choose [music] from.
In 2008, the first feline station master
was Basu, as in bus, named after the cat
bus from My Neighbor Toro. After that,
it was Love, then Peach, then the
current station master, Sakura. Love,
Peach, and Sakura are all related, by
the way. There's some lovely artwork of
the former station masters, and I'm
assuming this giant plush is of the
original station [music] master bus. The
train is now set to leave. So, Sakura is
finishing off her work shift for the
day.
With visiting the cat station off my
personal checklist, we headed over to
Ochuku, the former post town from the
Edeto period. Back then, over 150 years
ago, travelers would rest, eat, and shop
here. Many of the that roof buildings
have been preserved as they were before,
so you can get an idea of what it would
have been like back then. The money shot
that all modern-day visitors are going
for is up this stairway. [music] And
here it is, a great view of the town
below. And if you're into people
watching, you only need to back up a
little bit. And there's plenty of
activity.
While I would have loved to try eating
at one of the shops, we had a
reservation at a Wakapamei restaurant
that we had to rush to.
>> [music]
>> machine.
[music]
So wapa is the round containers and
wapameshi is the dish cooked in those
containers.
>> It's a chopstick.
>> So instead of chopsticks, they give you
a leak.
>> And but are you supposed to eat the leak
while you're eating the soba?
>> You bite as you go. It's pretty.
>> But look how you going to This is
>> You can do it.
good though.
>> Look at this. I don't know how you're
supposed to eat it.
Got
>> I wonder if people actually do this for
show. I'll need gum after this.
[laughter]
>> Every time they eat this, I see people
take like maybe two or three bites for
like
>> and then they use a chopsticks. Yeah.
Perhaps some of you recognize that other
voice. It's Loretta from Kamushi Chan.
She's simultaneously visiting a
different part of Fukushima, but our
paths crossed at this restaurant. So, we
chatted a bit about travel in Japan's
countryside, the Inaka. And for those
curious, I'll put the link to her video
in the [music] description. I hear
there's a lot of chatter online about
over tourism.
>> Mhm.
>> And um but when I'm going to visit the
Inaka, I don't really see that that
much. I don't know about you. I feel
like when you go into the Inaka, it's
almost like that time capsule of Japan
is still out there. Back in the day,
like 15, 20ish years ago, it was like
there was no Google Maps. There was
nothing. There was no, you couldn't
Google where to go. You just had to like
get there. There probably wasn't even
Wi-Fi and there was like you would just
walk and kind of discover and explore,
but you were always like the one person,
[laughter]
>> like the one weirdo walking around. Like
I feel like that's the same vibe you get
when you go to Inaka
>> nowadays. Yeah. And then but yeah, other
other than that like I don't really get
a sense of like over tourism unless I
seek out crowded places.
>> Yesterday I visited this little castle
and there's like basically no one there.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> And we were comparing it to we went to
Himeji just um a few months before and
it was just insanely packed. Like
shoulder-to-shoulder we got stuck in the
top floor.
>> Are you Oh my gosh. Really?
>> No. We couldn't get out for like 10 or
15 minutes. We're just packed.
>> It's just so much nicer. It's so much
more refreshing to just walk and still
see places and not have to really worry
if it lives up to an expectation.
>> It's like it's just yours.
>> Yeah.
>> Your little gem. The Japanese people in
the stores are used to looking at phones
and apps. Like I feel like 5 years ago
you would say like do you have this? And
they would be like what are you showing
me right now? But like people are just
used to interacting now. It's a lot
easier
>> if you want to get especially to really
local places. Sometimes there's places
that you can't book things online. You
have to call and confirm in person that
they have availability. They can make a
reservation. So,
>> yeah, that's for sure. And that's kind
of like the fun spots though, right?
>> Yeah. I think that's the probably the
extra hurdle that still makes it that
you can get to these places where
there's not a lot of over tourism
because they have those hurdles of
either having to use a Japanese website
to book
>> or having to call in person to confirm
that you can get there and paying cash.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. I kind of like those
slightly not barriers to entry, but like
the like hurdles.
>> Yeah.
>> Those little hurdles make it they kind
of protect it a little bit. So
>> So what we're saying is that if you want
a chiller, less touristy experience in
Japan, a trip like ours in Fukushima
will get you that. For example, after
lunch, we visited the school for samurai
children, Nishan, and we essentially had
the whole place to ourselves.
There's swords everywhere. Katana,
>> first school lunch in Japan
though. And did I mention they have an
archery range where you can hone your
non-existent skills at shooting arrows.
Well, maybe you have skills, but we
definitely did not.
Do you see the arrow in the middle of
the target?
>> Yeah. That was sensei's. The rust on the
ground there, those are echoes.
Boy,
[music]
>> thank you very much.
>> But it wasn't like I was much better.
service.
>> Time to embarrass myself.
>> In Japanese, [music] they use the word
service to mean complimentary. So, we
received many rounds of service arrows.
>> [laughter]
>> Yay! I'm done.
Okay. [laughter]
[laughter]
Thank you very much.
night. I can't live here. No toilets.
>> This is Turka Castle. During the Boschin
war, the castle [music] was devastated
by a month of shelling using western
artillery. It was later dismantled to
then be rebuilt in various stages
starting in 1965. [music] The whole
castle is now a museum, and I quite
enjoyed the exhibits. I especially found
the helmets of the various military
[music] commanders quite fascinating.
Now, I can see that some of the video
games I played while young weren't
exaggerating the armor worn. [music]
Despite what you're thinking, the mangji
symbol represents nice stuff like
eternity and good fortune. It was Hitler
that appropriated the [music] swatika as
a Nazi symbol.
At the top of the castle, there's an
outdoor observation deck. The view of
Aizu Wakamatsu at night from a perch up
on the castle was a fitting way to end
our day and our trip to Fukushima.
As always, thanks for watching. See you
next time. Peace. If you've traveled
outside of major Japanese cities, what
was your experience like?
[screaming]
[laughter]
My my [laughter]
my